Guide to the Abraham Unger Papers TAM.157
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Cases, 1936-1974
  - Wilson, James (Petitioner-Appellant) v. Ryan, Timothy, Warden of City Prison, the Bronx (Respondant): Legal Documents, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Wilson, James (Petitioner-Appellant) v. Ryan, Timothy, Warden of City Prison, the Bronx (Respondant): Legal Documents, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Series III: National Lawyers Guild, 1930s-1970s
  - Administrative Committee, 1941-1957 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Amicus Curiae Brief in Connection with Application for Reduction of Sentence, 1949-1950, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Appeal to Join American Lawyers, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Banquet and Finance Committee, Apr 21, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - A Bill to Authorize the United States to Acquire the Means of Production of Munitions and Armaments for National Defense Purposes, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn Trust Chapter, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Celebrity Quotes Endorsing NLG, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Clippings, 1938-1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Committee for Legal Assistance in the South, 1964, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Committee on Bill of Rights, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Committee on Government Operations, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Committee on Immigration and Naturalization, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Committee on International Law and Relations, 1953-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Committee on International Law and Relations: Cuba (Correspondence, Statements), 1961 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Legal Services, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Committee on Professional Problems, 1948-1953 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Committee on Public Relations, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Committee on United Nations, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Committee to Assist Southern Lawyers, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Conference on Civil Rights and Discrimination (New York, NY Oct 10-12, 1952), 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Conferences, 1939-1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Constitution (Proposed Amendments), undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Constitutional Liberties Committee, 1948-1966 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Constitutional Rights and Liberties Committee, 1948-1956, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Convention (Washington D.C., Feb 20-22, 1937) (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Convention (Chicago, IL, Feb 12-14, 1939) (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Convention (Chicago, IL, Feb 20-22, 1943) (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Convention (Chicago, IL, Feb 20-23, 1948) (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Convention (Detroit, MI, Feb 18-22, 1949), 1948-1949 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Convention (New York City, NY, May 5-7, 1950) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Convention (Chicago, IL, Oct 12-14, 1951) (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Convention (New York City, NY, Feb 21-23, 1953) (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Convention (Chicago, IL, Nov 19-21, 1954) (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Convention (Chicago, IL, Nov 19-21, 1954): Reports (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Convention (Chicago, IL, Nov 19-21, 1954): Resolutions (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Convention (Detriot, MI, Feb 10-13, 1956) (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Convention (New York City, NY, Feb 21-24, 1957) (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Convention (Chicago, IL, Nov 7-10, 1958) (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Convention (San Francisco, CA, Jul 28-31, 1960) (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Convention (Detroit, MI, Feb 22-25, 1962) (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Convention (Detroit, MI, Feb 21-23, 1964) (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Convention (New York, NY, Feb 10-13, 1967) (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Convention (Boulder, CO, Jul 28-Aug 1, 1971) (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Convention (Austin, TX, Feb 15-19, 1973) (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Convention (Minneapolis, MI, Aug 8-12, 1974) (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1945 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1933, 1949, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Defense of the Bar, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Designation of NLG as a Subversive Oragnization (Legal Documents), 1954, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Detroit Chapter, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Disbarment, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - District of Columbia Chapter, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Draft Counseling, 1967-1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Labor Law Committee, Dec 14, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Labor Relations, 1940-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Lawyers' Committee for Democracy, c. 1940 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Lawyers Guild Review (Correspondence, Notices), 1950-1961 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Lawyers Guild Review (Editorial Board Meeting Minutes, Correspondence), 1947-1958, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Lawyers Guild Review (Manuscripts), undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Lawyers Guild Review (Manuscripts About Czechoslovakia), undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Lawyers Guild Review (Records), 1950-1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Lawyers Guild Review (Typescripts), undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Lawyers Guild Review (Typescripts), 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Lists of Names and Memberships of US Lawyers, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Memorandum of Law with Respect to the Sale of Newspapers in Subways, c. 1930s (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Military Law, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - National Committee on Civil Rights and Liberties, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - National Committee on Social Legislation (Propositions on Disability Benefits, Housing, Rent Control, and Unemployment), 1947-1948, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - National Executive Board (Correspondence, Minutes), 1937-1950 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - National Executive Board (Correspondence, Minutes), 1951-1954 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - National Executive Board (Correspondence, Minutes), 1955-1965 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - New York State Legislative Conferences, 1947, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - New York State Legislative Conferences, 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Press Fund Committee, 1930s (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Public Relations Committee/Subcommittee on the Clergy, undated, 1945-1954 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Publications, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Records, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Records, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Records, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Records, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Records, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Records, 1940-1942 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Records, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Records, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Records, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Records, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Records, c. 1950 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Records, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Records, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Records, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Records, 1954-1956 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Records, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Records, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Records, 1959-1960 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Records, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Records, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Records, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Records, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Records, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Records, 1970-1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Resolution: Academic Freedom, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Resolution: Anti-War, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Resolution Committee, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Resolutions: Subversive Activities Control Act (McCarran Act), 1955 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Atomic Peace and Nuclear Weapons, 1958, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Resolutions and Statements: China, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Civil Rights, 1947-1957, 1964, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Cold War, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Communism, 1954, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Germany, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Resolutions and Statements: House Committee on Un-American Activities, 1948-1962, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Resolutions and Statements: International Relations and Law (Including New International Law), undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Korea, 1951, 1953, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Labor Law, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Resolutions and Statements: The Lawyers Guild, 1954-1960, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Lawyers Welfare, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Resolutions and Statements: The Legal System, 1948-1958, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Legal Workers Cases (Disbarment, Defending Unpopular Cases), undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Mundt-Nixon Bill, 1948-1950 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Resolutions and Statements: The North Atlantic Pact, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Palestine, 1948, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Segregation, 1954, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Smith Act, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Social Welfare, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Supreme Court, 1958, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Resolutions and Statements: Taxes, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Resolutions and Statements: World War 2, c. 1940s (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - San Francisco Bay Area Chapter, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Statement Acclaiming Church Council Statement, Mar 20, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Statement: Discrimination Against Women, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Statement: German American Bund, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Statement: Job Placement of Graduating Law Students, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Statement: Ludlow Amendment and the Convention, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Statement: McCarthyism, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Student Division, 1952, undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Syllabi, undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
- Series IV: National Lawyers Guild: New York City Chapter, 1930s-1970s
  - Administrative Committee, 1949-1952 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Board of Directors (Correspondence, Minutes), 1938-1949, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Board of Directors (Correspondence, Minutes), 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Board of Directors (Correspondence, Minutes), 1952 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Board of Directors (Correspondence, Minutes), 1953 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Board of Directors (Correspondence, Minutes), 1954 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Board of Directors (Correspondence, Minutes), 1955 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Board of Directors (Correspondence, Minutes), 1956-1958 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Civil Liberties Committee on Discrimination and War, Jan 15, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1964-1971 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Freedom of Advocacy, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Independence of the Bar, 1957-1958, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Labor Law and Industrial Relations, 1947-1948, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Committee on Social Legislation, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Committee on Taxation and Finance, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Committee to Revise the Constitution and By-Laws, 1952, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Cultural and Social Events (Dinners, Lectures, Theatres), 1942-1968, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Executive Committee (Correspondence, Minutes), 1937-1957, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Juidicial Candidates, Evaluations - New York City, New York State, 1937-1953, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Juidiciary Committee (Correspondence, Abraham Unger's Handwritten Notes), 1937-1954 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Labor Law Committee, 1955, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - List of Names: Memberships, New York City Lawyers, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Memorandums, Resolutions, Statements, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Military Law Projects, 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - New York Guild Lawyer, 1938-1958 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - New York State Court Reform, 1955-1959, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - New York State Court Reform (Clippings), 1955-1959, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - New York State Court Reform (Correspondence), 1955-1958 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - New York State Court Reform (Manuscript: "Concurrent Resolution of the Senate and Assembly"), undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - New York State Court Reform (Notes), 1955, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Picketing, Strike, 1936, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Records, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Records, c. 1930s (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Records, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Records, 1940-1941 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Records, 1942-1946 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Records, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Records, c. 1949 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Records, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Records, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Records, 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Records, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Records, 1957-1960 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Records, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Records, 1963-1969 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Records, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Statements: German American Bund, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Series V: Subject Files, 1930s-1970s
  - Abzug, Bella, 1970, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Academic Freedom: Clippings, 1947, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Ad Hoc Committee For Lawyers and Justice, 1969, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Adams, Thomas Boylston (D): Speech Before His Campaign Workers, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Agriculture and Markets Law and Penal Law Relating to the Sale of Kosher Meat and Food, State of New York, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - American Bar Association: Attempt to Bar NLG Members from ABA (Correspondence, Statements), 1937-1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - American Bar Associations (Clippings), 1955-1957, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - American Bar Association: Policy Statement, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - American Birobidjan Committee, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - American Civil Liberties Union and New York City Civil Liberties Committee, 1947, 1954, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - American Committee for Anti-Nazi Literature, undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - American Committee for Indonesian Independence, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born, 1948-1967 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - American Friends Committee, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - American Labor Party, 1948-1952 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - American Peace Crusade, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - American Socialist, 1956, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Americans Sponsoring Committee for Representation at the World Peace Congress, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Amnesty International, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Anti Red Ordinance, Birmingham, Alabama, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Appellate Division, New York State Supreme Court, 1955, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Automobile Accident Laws, May 24, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Atomic Energy, 1942, 1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Bar Committee Afgainst Test Oath Bill For Lawyers, 1949-1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Bartunek Seibert Bill, Cleveland, OH, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Ben Davis Ball Committee, 1949, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Bianchi, William J.: State Senator Candidate' Voting Record, c. 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Bichovsky, Jacob, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Bill of Duties for the American People, c. 1940s (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Bill of Rights (Conference, Defender), 1949 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Black Question, 1940-1965, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Black Question (Clippings), 1962-1969, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Blynn, Arthur; Kenneth Shorter, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Burns, Robert E.: Extradition Before the Governor of New Jersey, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Callahan Act, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors, 1963-1966, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Chicago 8 Conspiracy Trial, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - China, 1944, 1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Citizens Committee for Constitutional Liberties: "Ban Loyalty Oaths and Political Inquisitions in the New York State Constitution" by Paul L. Ross, c. 1967 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Citizens Committee to Elect George Blake Charney District Attorney of New York, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Citizens Committee to Protect the Right of Counsel, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Citizens Conference for Peace (June 7-8, 1949), 1949, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Citizens Emergency Defense Conference: "Defend Our Civil Rights" by Judge Hubert T. Delany, c. 1953 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Civil Liberties, 1941-1964 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Civil Rights Congress, 1948-1964, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Civil Rights Laws, 1939, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Civil Rights Violations (African-Americans), 1948-1950 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Clark, Grenville: "A Settlement with Russia - It's Necessity for World Federation" Address at the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, Feb 7, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Collazo, Oscar: Puerto Rican Political Prisoner, 1968-1972, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Columbia University Strike, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Columbia University Strike (Clippings), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Columbia University Strike (Legal Documents), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Columbia University Strike (Notes), 1968 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Committee for a Fair Trial For Drasa Mihailovich, undated, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Committee on Character and Fitness, Supreme Court, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Committee on Social Security for Doctors, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Committee To Abolish the House Committee on Un-American Activities: Clippings, 1949-1963, undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Committee To Abolish the House Committee on Un-American Activities, National, 1961-1964, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Committee To Abolish the House Committee on Un-American Activities, New York Council, 1961-1962, undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Committee To Abolish the House Committee on Un-American Activities, New York Council, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Committee To Defeat the Smith Act, undated (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Committee to Defend Carlos Feliciano, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Communist Control Act 1954, Jun 22, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Communist League of America, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Communist Party USA: Broadcasting Correspondence, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Communist Party USA (Clippings), 1946-1972, undated (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Communist Party USA: Constitution and By-Laws, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Communist Party USA: Deportation, early 1950s (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Communist Party USA: Education, 1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Communist Party USA: Electoral and Political Statements, 1936-1949 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Communist Party USA: Internal Documents, 1950-1961, undated (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Communist Party USA: Manuscript on the Un-American Thomas-Rankin Committee, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Conscientious Objectors (Clippings), 1967 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Consumer Issues, 1971-1974 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Council on African Affairs, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Criminal Syndicalism (Selected Bibliography), undated (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Cuba, 1961-1963, undated (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Daily Worker Suepoena by Queens County District Attorney, Apr 3, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Davis, Benjamin, late 1940s, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Devany-Martin Bill (Proposal to Bar CommunistS from Civil Service), 1939 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Disarmament (Includes Speeches at the United Nations), 1951-1954 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Doran, Lillian Adele: Motion Written by Margolis, Ben, Oct 27, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Douglas, William O.: Address at the Annual Dinner of the Rhode Island Bar Association, Oct 29, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Dubois Memorial Committee, Jan 22, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee, 1953-1966, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (Clippings), 1953-1962, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee (Fliers, Pamphlets, Publications), 1953-1964, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Emergency Detention Act: Repeal, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Epton, Bill: Puerto Rican Politican Prisoner, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Espionage Laws: Congresssional Records, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Fairplay for Cuba Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Feinberg Law, 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Feinberg Law (Clippings), 1949 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Finance, Banking, and Economy Related Legislation, 1920s-1940s (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Financial Employees Guild: Local 96, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Franklin, Mitchell: Writings, 1958, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - The Freeedom and Peace Party, New York, NY, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - The Freedom Club - Independent Democrats, New York, New York, 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Freedom from Fear Committee, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Gordon, Leon: "Undesirable Lady" - A Melodrama in Three Acts, c. 1933 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Greater New York CIO Council, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Greater New York School of Anti-Communism, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Greece: Civil War and the Aftermath, 1948-1952 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Hiss, Alger: Daily News Editorial, Nov 26, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC): Clippings, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - House Committee on Un-American Activities (HUAC), Opposition to, 1948-1968, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Immigration: House of Representatives' Resolutions, 1940, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Independent Citizen's Committee for the Election of Paul O'Dwyer to Congress, Sept 16, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Industrial Union of Marine and Shipbuilding Workers of America, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Initiating Committee of Bronx Lawyers for Wallace, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - International Association of Democratic Jurists, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - International Association of Democratic Lawyers (Congress Programs, Declarations, Resolutions), 1948-1970 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - International Association of Democratic Lawyers (Correspondence), 1948-1964 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - International Association of Democratic Lawyers (Manuscripts), 1947, undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - International Juridical Association, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - International Labor Defense, National, 1935-1941 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - International Labor Defense, National: Press Releases, 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - International Labor Defense: New York State, 1936-1937, 1956, undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - International Union of Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers (Mine-Mill Act), 1959 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Israel-Palestinian Conflict, 1947-1969 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Japan Federation of Bar Associations, Dec 8, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Jewish Peoples Fraternal Order: "A Petition to Outlaw Anti-Semitism and Anti-Negro Race Hate Propaganda", 1949 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Jewish Question, 1940-1947,1969, undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - John J. Abt Testimonial Committee, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Joint Committee to Defend WPA Workers, 1939-1942 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Labor Research Association: Railroad Retirement Act, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Lawyers Committee on American Policy Towards Vietnam, 1969, undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Lawyers Committee to End the War, 1969-1970, undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Lawyers Committee to End the War, 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Lawyers Committee to Reform the Marijuana Laws, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Lawyers Security League's Letter to Franklin Roosevelt, Mar 5, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Legal Aid Society: Up Against the Wall (SDS Flier), c. 1970s (Box 9, Folder 48)